ISLAM HEGAZY

Sr Front-End Developer

With A Passion For Beautiful Design And Effective UI

I've always sought out opportunities and challenges that are meaningful to me. As a front-end developer, I enjoy using myobsessive attention to detail, my unequivocal love for makingthings, and my mission-driven work ethic to literally change the world. I have experience working, providing responsive front-end development websites.

EXPERIENCE

OLIT COMPANY

3-2021 - 6/2022

Sr Front End Developer

Design and develop Front-End web application using angular +2

Design robust, high-performance, low-maintenance, and documented solutions

Work closely with other team members from the early stages of design all the way through identifying and resolving issues

Develop new web applications that communicate with backend web APIs

Suggest and demonstrate efficient designs & technologies for applications

Support other members of the team

IDEALWAVES COMPANY

Sr Front End Developer

12/2019 - 3/2021

Represent the front-end and interactive technologies in development and discussion of new modules and features for LocalCircles web.

Take lead and responsibility for understanding the front-end and interactive requirements for releases and plan iteratively to meet the requirement.

Identify the issues reported by the team and users, prioritize them and plan the fixes for each release.

Collaborate with the product and technology team and lead the UI implementation across development and testing phase

Take lead and support Search Engine Optimization, Progressive Enhancement Accessibility.

Build rich, dynamic client-side interfaces, Troubleshoot issues reported by users and fix them with a quick turn-around

Come up with a user experience design for basic features and enhancements

Find and implement features to improve the performance of the web and mobile platforms

Work with the business and marketing teams to understand the perspective of the users



CONTACT

010-968-22565

islam.ab.hegazy@gmail.com

PORTFOLIO

View my full portfolio of web design and projects



https://islamhegazy.herokuapp.com/#/portfolio

SKILLS

- HTML/Bootstrap/Materialize
- CSS/SASS/LESS
- JavaScript/JQuery/Angular+2/React/Vue
- Git/GitHub/Gitlab/TFS
- Api/Json/Ajax
- Photoshop/Illustrator/Xd
- Familiarity With PHP and ASP.Net
- Unit testing
- RESTful and JSON and security/REST APIs
- CI/CD
- Agile development methodologies

LANGUAGES

- English
- Arabic

EDUCATION

FACULTY OF COMPUTER AND INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

Bachelor degree in information technology GPA: 3.15/4

EBTKARAAT COMPANY 3/2017 - 12/2019

Front End Developer

- . Implementing web design and development principles to build stable software
- . Bringing mockups to life using web technologies
- . Collaborating closely with the team to support projects during all phases of delivery
- . Building websites and apps that are responsive and usable. Monitoring website performance and rectifying front-end-related issues
- . Communicating technical issues in an understandable manner to the team and clients
- . Identifying innovative ideas and proof of concepts according to project requirements

Providing guidance and troubleshooting support to clients

. Maintaining an organized workflow using a project manage-ment tool (like GitHub)

Testing to identify bugs and technical issues before and after deploying

.Documenting bug reports, tickets, and any code changes

EBTKARAAT COMPANY

6/2016 - 3/2017

Front end developer internship